

Abdulla Jaseem

MERN STACK DEVELOPER

About

Self-taught software developer with experience in Node.js, React, and Redux. Have a good knowledge of JavaScript and have been working with React. Confident and have the ability to build full-stack web applications from scratch and have a keen eye for detail. Also experienced in working with databases, such as MongoDB, and have a strong understanding of the MERN stack.

PROJECT EXPERIENCE

BOOKPAD

November 2022 - Present

MERN Stack web app

- A social media app aims to connect users through the sharing of information and personal experiences. Users will be able to create profiles, post updates, and interact with other users through comments. JWT is used to ensure the security of our users data,
- React, Redux, Node, MongoDB, Express, JWT, TailwindCSS, MeterialUi, JWT access token, Cloudinary, Register and login with Google, Verify account with email, Socket.io for chat and AWS EC2 & AWS Amplify.
- Future plans are to continually update and improve the app with new features and functionality in the future, like adding mini games and advertisements.
- Link: https://www.bookpad.site/
- gitHub: https://github.com/JassimJasi/bookpad_frontend
 - https://github.com/JassimJasi/bookpad_backend

Dr-Crptr

July 2022 - August 2022

A complete Ecommerce website which sells furniture.

- A ecommerce website aims to provide customers with a convenient and easy
 way to shop for furniture online. The website will allow users to browse and
 purchase a variety of furniture items, including tables, chairs, and more.
- Node.js, MongoDB, Express.js, Bootstrap, HBS, Twilio, OAuth2, Razorpay, AWS, Nginx,SweetAlert2.
- Razorpay payment integration, Twilio OTP and Google OAuth2 authentication.
 SweetAlert2(Confirmation and alerts). Admin can manage users, products, orders, offers(coupons) and posters. and Admin can create new categories
- Future plans are to continually update and improve the website with new features and functionality in the future.
- Link: https://drcrptr.shop/
- gitHub: https://github.com/JassimJasi/Dr-Crptr

INCUBATION MANAGEMENT

July 2022 - July 2022

MERN Stack web app

- Incubation Management for companies for booking slots with Mern stack.
- Companies can apply for physical space and can view the status of their application.
- Admin verify the application and manage the status of application.
- Admin can allocate slots for respective companies.
- Technologies Used: React.js, Node.js, MongoDB, Express.js, Bootstrap, MUI, JWT

CONTACT

- My website
- +91 8848088581
- · jassimsadanamks@gmail.com
- Linkedin
- GitHub

SKILLS

- MFRN Stack
- Full stack
- · Web development
- · React.js
- Node.js

Front-end

- JavaScript
- · HTML/HTML5
- · CSS / SASS
- React
- Redux
- JQuery
- Bootstrap
- TailwindCSS
- Ajax
- Axios

Back-End:

- Node.js
- · Express.js
- MongoDb
- · JWT
- RestAPI
- · JWT
- RestAPI

Familiar:

- GIT / GitHub
- · AWS (EC2 and Amplify)
- C programing language
- Java
- · Data Structure
- Nginx
- Redux Toolkit

EDUCATION

BROTOTYPE

MERN Stack Developer (Trainee) Calicut,Kerala — May 2022 -Present

MOUNT SEENA COLLEGE

BA English

Palakkad, Kerala — May 2016 - April 2019

OTHER

English

Malayalam